A Calendar of The Jefferson Papers of the University of Virginia
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series I: Dated Materials
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to JOSEPH CARRINGTON CABELL, Williamsburg., 1813 November 7.; ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Enclosure: AD. 1 pp. #201. Partly printed: Cabell 8-9; B of R VI 58 (MS. in DLC).
    Bill to extend powers of the Rivanna Co. Requests return of Say's Traité d'economie politique. References to Col. [Nimrod] Bramham, [George] Divers, and Dabney Minor.
    [1257]
  - JOHN BARNES, Georgetown, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1813 November 10.; ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Purchase of bill of exchange from George Williams; acknowledgement by General Kosciuszko of money received from Russell & Morton.
    [1258]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to THOMAS HORNSBY, Shelbyville, Ky., 1813 November 11.; ALS. 3 pp. File draft. Endorsed by T. J. McGregor Library, #564.
    Requests that he meet with Gov. Christopher Greenup to adjust the differences regarding confirmation of Frances Henderson Hornsby's deed for her share of the Bennett Henderson estate, a deed made while she was a minor. References to James L. Henderson, Eliza Henderson, Elizabeth Henderson, John Henderson, and Craven Peyton.
    [1259]
  - PATRICK GIBSON, Richmond, to THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1813 November 13.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    Sends money. Flour prices.
    [2853]
  - JOSEPH CARRINGTON CABELL, Williamsburg, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1813 November 29.; ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #2791. Printed: Cabell 10-12.
    Bill concerning T. J. and the Rivanna River Co. will pass the Virginia Assembly. Disagrees with T. J. on the length of the charter. Prefers Jean Baptiste Say's book on political economy to Adam Smith's.
    [1260]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, [Monticello], to BARON ALEXANDER VON HUMBOLDT., 1813 December 6.; ALS. 4 pp. Photostat. #38-257. Original in DLC. Printed: Ford IX 430-433; L & B XIV 20-25; B of R VI 224 (MS. in DLC).
    Acquaintance with José Correa da Serra. Receipt of Von Humboldt's books on astronomical observations and on New Spain. Revolutions in Latin America may lead to military despotisms. Important that American governments be separated from the "broils of Europe". Unprincipled policy of England has prevented a peaceful policy with the Indians. Brutalization and extermination of Indians compared to treatment of Ireland. British Arrowsmith and American Pike guilty of plagiarism. Delay in the publication of the journal of the Lewis and Clark expedition. Gift of tobacco seed to Von Humboldt.
    [1261]
  - JOSEPH CARRINGTON CABELL, Richmond, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1813 December 8.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #2791. Printed: Cabell 12-13.
    Books forwarded through General Moore. Reelection of Governor Barbour expected despite discontent throughout the state. Consultation with Charles Everett and Jesse W. Garth relative to the petition of the Rivanna River Co.
    [1262]
  - JOHN BARNES, Georgetown, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1813 December 12.; ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Remittance to General Kosciuszko via George Williams and Morton & Russell is not possible. Congratulations on Thomas M. Randolph, Jr.'s safe return.
    [1263]
  - PATRICK GIBSON, Richmond, to THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1813 December 21.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    T. J.'s note. Flour prices. Embargo has stopped West Indies trade.
    [2854]
  - ELIZABETH HENDERSON. DEPOSITION., 1813 December 25.; ADS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. McGregor Library, #564.
    Deposition denying knowledge of sale of her daughter's property to Craven Peyton by James L. Henderson until several years after the transaction.
    [1264]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to CHARLES CLAY., 1813 December 28.; ALS. 1 pp. McGregor Library, #2288. Printed: B of R VI 86 (MS. in DLC).
    Price of Mr. Forbes' wool-carding and cotton-carding machines.
    [1265]
  - PATRICK GIBSON, Richmond, to THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1813 December 29.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    Flour sales and w heat prices.
    [2855]
  - DABNEY MINOR, Albemarle County, to JOSEPH CARRINGTON CABELL, Richmond., 1813 December 30.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #201. Printed: Cabell 10.
    Agreement between T. J. and the Rivanna Company directors that bill be passed. References to [Charles] Everett and E. Garth.
    [1266]
  - [W. & R. MITCHELL]. ACCOUNTS AGAINST THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1813.; D. 2 items. One endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Accounts of the milling of the Poplar Forest wheat crop.
    [1268]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON ACCOUNT WITH DR. WILLIAM STEPTOE., 1813-1814.; ADS. 1 pp. In hand of William Steptoe; endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    Services rendered and medications prescribed. Patients include slaves Aggy, Maria, Ambrose, and Sally. Mentions Mr. Clay.
    [2857]
  - JOSÉ FRANCISCO CORREA DE SERRA, PLAN FOR A BOTANICAL GARDEN FOR A PUBLIC SCHOOL., [1813-1820].; D. 3 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photostat. #7254-b.
  - THOMAS HORNSBY, Shelbyville, Ky., to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1814 January 9.; ALS. 3 pp. Endorsed by T. J. McGregor Library, #564.
    Sends Elizabeth Henderson's deposition regarding the shares of the minor children of Bennett Henderson. Asks about John Henderson's mill race. Value of land mortgaged to Craven Peyton as security for property near Big Bone Lick, Ky., he purchased from James L. Henderson in Virginia. References to William Meriwether and Christopher Greenup.
    [1269]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to PATRICK GIBSON., 1814 January 13.; ALS. 1 pp. #9371-o.
    Regarding flour prices, and 100 barrels of flour T. J. has ready for sale.
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to THOMAS COOPER., 1814 January 16.; L. 3 pp. Copy by Ellen Randolph. #38-130. Printed: L & B XIV 54-63 (minor variations); B of R VI 95 (MS. in DLC).
    Congratulates him on his edition of Justinian's Institutes, but wishes he had put his time into Bracton's De Legibus Angliae. Would like to see Blackstone's work supplemented by specification of particular cases of which his principles are the essence. Cannot give name of author of Commentaries on Montesquieu [Destutt de Tracy]; manuscript now in T. J.'s hands.
    [1270]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to JOSEPH CARRINGTON CABELL., 1814 January 17.; ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #201. Printed: Cabell 13-16; L & B XIV 67-70; B of R VI 58 (MS. in DLC).
    Encloses letters written to John Wayles Eppes regarding public debt, banks, and money. Advises gradual reduction of paper money in Virginia. Favors division of state into hundreds or wards.
    [1271]
  - PATRICK GIBSON, Richmond, to THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1814 January 19.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    Sends money. Flour prices and sales, some to Alexandria, Va.
    [2858]
  - JOSEPH CARRINGTON CABELL, Richmond, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1814 January 23.; ALS. 3 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #2791. Printed: Cabell 16-18.
    Expresses limited approval of a state banking system. Voted for chartering Bank of Virginia. Restriction of the residence of a member of the House of Representatives to the district from which he was elected. Bill respecting the Rivanna River Company. Reasons for the division of state into wards.
    [1272]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to JOSEPH CARRINGTON CABELL, Richmond., 1814 January 31.; ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #201. Printed: Cabell 19-21; Ford IX 451-453; L & B XIV 82-85; TJR IV 238-239; B of R VI 58 (MS. in DLC).
    Receipt of Say's Traité d'economie politique. Opinions as to whether states may prescribe any qualifications for members of Congress not contained in the Constitution. Line of demarcation between powers of the state and national governments. Maintains an interest in only two subjects: public education, and the division of counties into wards or hundreds.
    [1273]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to MRS. ELIZABETH TRIST, at Mr. Gilmer's, near Henry Court House., 1814 February 1.; ALS. 1 pp. Photostat. Original owned by John R. Burke. #5422.
    Ellen Wayles Randolph's translation of letter. Martha's new daughter Septimia Ann. Children have whooping cough. Thomas Mann Randolph, Jr. probably leaves in spring to campaign T. J. Randolph's girl friend at Warren. Mr. Gilmer's brothers well. Dr. Gilmer left Milton for place bought from Key near Mr. Minor.
    [2859]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to JEREMIAH GOODMAN, Poplar Forest., 1814 February 3.; ALS. 1 pp. #3177. Owned by Thomas Jefferson Memorial Foundation.
    Remittance through Patrick Gibson of Richmond. Instructions for sowing clover, shipment of beef and tobacco, rationing of salt. No flour sold. Orders to kill all dogs in excess of two, since they are taxable.
    [1274]
  - JOSEPH CARRINGTON CABELL, Richmond, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1814 February 5.; ALS. 3 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #2791. Printed: Cabell 21-23.
    Assembly's action on residence requirements for Congressmen. Passage of the Rivanna River Company bill in form agreed upon by T. J. and [Dabney] Minor. Bill to charter bank at Wheeling.
    [1275]
  - PATRICK GIBSON, Richmond, to THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1814 February 8.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    Nail rod, corks, and powder by Mr. Johnson. Flour prices. T. J. accounts with Samuel P. Adams, James Brown, Jr., and Ignatius J. Dick.
    [2860]
  - JOHN BARNES, Georgetown, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1814 February 9.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Inability to make remittance to George Williams for General Kosciuszko.
    [1276]
  - JOHN BARNES, Georgetown, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1814 February 11.; ALS. 4 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Confidence in the credit of the Bank of Pennsylvania; opposes disposal of General Kosciuszko's bank stock. Beneficial results of banks overshadow their evils.
    [1277]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to JOHN BARNES, Georgetown., 1814 February 23.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Photostat. #2224. Original owned by Wayne M. Hart.
    Orders to convert Kosciuszko's stock in the Bank of Pennsylvania to government stock. Lack of confidence in banks. Failure of the Manhattan Bank.
    [1278]
  - PATRICK GIBSON, Richmond, to THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1814 February 26.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    T. J.'s note falls due. New one enclosed for signature. Prospect of peace and trade with Holland influence tobacco market, but not flour prices.
    [2861]
  - JOHN BARNES, Georgetown, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1814 February 27.; ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Conversion of General Kosciuszko's shares in the Bank of Pennsylvania to government stock. Remittance to General K. Importance of stopping the increase of banks. Effect of the failure of the Bank of Manhattan on other banks.
    [1279]
  - PATRICK GIBSON, Richmond, to THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1814 March 2.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    Note may not be received. Will pay anyway, renew new one when received. Flour prices. Encloses money.
    [2862]
  - MARTIN DAWSON & CO., Milton, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1814 March 4.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    T. J.'s note to Craven Peyton for corn purchases. Will accept draft on Richmond or cash at Charlottesville.
    [2863]
  - JOSEPH CARRINGTON CABELL, Carysbrook, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1814 March 6.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. #2791-a. Printed: Cabell 24.
    Return of T. J.'s letters on banking and finance which have been shown to William C. Rives, [John?] Tucker, Thomas Ritchie, and [John H.] Cocke.
    [1280]
  - JOHN BARNES, Georgetown, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1814 March 8.; ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Considers transfer of T. J.'s and General Kosciuszko's Bank of Pennsylvania stock into loan office certificates unwise.
    [1281]
  - PATRICK GIBSON, Richmond, to THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1814 March 13.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    New procedure for handling T. J. s notes. Encloses notes. Flour sales.
    [2864]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to HENRY M. BRACKENRIDGE, Baton Rouge, 1814 March 16.; ALS. 1 pp. with attached address leaf. #14262.
    T. J. thanks Breckenridge for a copy of his recently published book, Views of Louisiana. Says book is a "valuable contribution towards the knowlege [sic] of a great country which nature has destined to become the most interesting portion of the western world."
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON RANDOLPH, Carysbrook, to THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1814 March 25.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Mr. Cary [Wilson J. Cary? Wilson M. Cary?] not at home.
    [1282]
  - PATRICK GIBSON, Richmond, to THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1814 March 26.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    Notes received. Encloses bank notes.
    [2865]
  - JOHN BARNES, Georgetown, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1814 April 5.; ALS. 3 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Figures proving Bank of Pennsylvania stock is preferable to loan office certificates.
    [1283]
  - PETER CARR to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1814 April 7 [date received].; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Carr-Cary Papers, #1231.
    Introducing the son of Dr. John D. Orr, a student of [Louis H.] Girardin.
    [1284]
  - JOHN BARNES, Georgetown, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1814 April 16.; ALS. 3 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    More facts to prove it is preferable to keep General Kosciuszko's Bank of Pennsylvania stock rather than converting to government stock.
    [1285]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to JOHN HARTWELL COCKE, Bremo., 1814 April 19.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Cocke Payers. Printed: B of R VI 89 (MS. in DLC). #3184.
    Offers to purchase a dark bay horse. Payment to be made after repeal of embargo permits sale of flour by Gibson & Jefferson. (Payment noted by Cocke's endorsement).
    [1286]
  - PATRICK GIBSON, Richmond, to THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1814 April 20.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    Repeal of restrictions brought flour buyers. Awaiting armistice. Mr. Albert bought tobacco. Powder.
    [2866]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to JOHN BARNES., 1814 April 25.; ALS. 4 pp. Photostat. #2283. Original owned by Polish Roman Catholic Union of America.
    T. J. discusses Tadeusz Kosciuszko's investments and the monetary situation of the United States.
  - JOHN BARNES, Georgetown, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1814 April 27.; ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Payment to General Armstrong for articles he forwarded for T. J. Madison has left for Montpellier. Reference to Mr. Harper and the Cossack dinners.
    [1287]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to SAMUEL BROWN., 1814 April 28.; ALS. 2 pp. #10594.
    T. J. sympathizes on the death of a loved one and comments on his own losses. He mentions the invention of a vapor bath, and the rise of household industries necessitated by the War of 1812, rejoices in the downfall of Napoleon, predicts bankruptcy for England, and requests a botanical specimen for Correa de Serra.
  - JOHN BARNES, Georgetown, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1814 May 2.; ALS. 3 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Agrees to conversion of General Kosciuszko's shares of Bank of Pennsylvania stock into government stock. Requests letter of introduction to James Monroe or to William H. Crawford in order to get a bill of exchange for remittance to General Kosciuszko.
    [1288]
  - JOHN BARNES, Georgetown, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1814 May 2.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Purchase of government stock for General Kosciuszko. Reference to the Bank of Columbia.
    [1289]
  - PATRICK GIBSON, Richmond, to THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1814 May 4.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    Sends bank notes. Flour sales await armistice.
    [2867]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to CRAVEN PEYTON, Monteagle., 1814 May 7.; ALS. 1 pp. Photostat. Original owned by John Peytom #5843-c.
    Encloses John Henderson's quitclaim for Peyton's use in defending against Elizabeth Henderson's claim that Peyton purchased for T. J. lands of minor Henderson children without her knowledge or permission. Mentions James Henderson, Thomas Hornsby.
    [2867-a]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to GEORGE W. CAMPBELL., 1814 May 8.; ALS. 1 pp. Photostat. #2283. Original owned by Polish Roman Catholic Union of America.
    T. J. asks Campbell if it is possible for the Treasury to arrange for Tadeusz Kosciuszko to receive payment of annual interest due him and interrupted because of the war.
  - JOHN BARNES, Georgetown, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1814 May 13.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Exchange of Kosciuszko's Bank of Pennsylvania stock for loan office certificates. Letter from Mr. Taylor regarding bank stock, government stock, and bills of exchange.
    [1290]
  - JOHN BARNES, Georgetown, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1814 May 18.; ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Sale of Kosciuszko's bank stock; purchase of government stock.
    [1291]
  - JOHN BARNES, Georgetown, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1814 May 24.; ALS. 3 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Sale of Kosciuszko's Bank of Pennsylvania stock. Remittance to Kosciuszko. Barnes in debt to purchase the General's government stock.
    [1292]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Poplar Forest, to ELIZABETH HOUSE TRIST., 1814 June 10.; ALS. 1 pp. Photostat. #5213-d.
  - PATRICK GIBSON, Richmond, to THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1814 June 13.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    Flour prices declining.
    [2868]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Poplar Forest, to THOMAS LAW., 1814 June 13.; ALS. 4 pp. #9561. Printed: L and B XIV,138-44.
    Received and read Law's Second Thoughts on Instinctive Impulses. Agrees with his philosophy of morality in man. Wollaston's theory whimsical. Truth, love of God not foundations of morality as atheists, Deists virtuous men. Diderot, d'Alembert, d'Holbach, Condorcet examples. Taste, egoism also false. Helvetius quoted, refuted. Man's innate moral instinct true basis of morality. Education a corrective for its absence. Virtue conditioned by utility. Lord Kames, in Principles of Natural Religion, says the same.
    [2868-a]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON in account with W. & R. MITCHELL., 1814 June 14.; D. 1 pp. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Bill for flour.
    [1293]
  - JOHN BARNES, Georgetown, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1814 June 16.; ALS. 3 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Sale of Kosciuszko's bank stock finally completed. Remittance to the General through Baring Brothers of London. Difficult trip from Philadelphia.
    [1294]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Poplar Forest, to ARCHIBALD ROBERTSON, Lynchburg., 1814 June 21.; ALS. 1 pp. File draft. Endorsed by T. J. McGregor Library, #564.
    Unable to meet payments since last year's flour unsold and bad drought this year. Peace orneutral commerce will help the growing crop. Plans tobacco crop. Mentions Patrick Gibson.
    [1295]
  - JOHN BARNES, Georgetown, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1814 June 22.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Purchase of bill of exchange to send remittance to General Kosciuszko. Encloses account with T. J. Mentions Mr. Nourse.
    [1296]
  - ACCOUNT OF TADUESZ KOSCIUSZKO WITH JOHN BARNES., 1814 June 22.; ADS. 1 pp. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Originally enclosed with Barnes' letter to T. J. of the same date.
  - JOHNS BARNES to TADUESZ KOSCIUSZKO., 1814 June 22.; ALS. 2 pp. Copy. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Originally enclosed with Barnes' letter to T. J. of 1814 June 27.
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Poplar Forest, to ARCHIBALD ROBINSON [ROBERTSON], Lynchburg., 1814 June 22.; ALS. 1 pp. File draft. Endorsed by T. J. McGregor Library, #564.
    Patrick Gibson is remitting money due to Jeremiah A. Goodman through Robertson. Order for sugar.
    [1297]
  - ARCHIBALD ROBERTSON, Lynchburg, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Poplar Forest., 1814 June 22.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. McGregor Library, #564.
    Hopes for payment from T. J. Will make remittance to Jeremiah Goodman.
    [1298]
  - JOHN BARNES, Georgetown, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1814 June 27.; ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Bowie & Kurtz' bill of exchange on William Murdock given to James Monroe to be transmitted to Baring Brothers for General Kosciuszko. Desire for peace among Federalists.
    [1300]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to TADEUSZ KOSCIUSZKO., 1814 June 28.; ALS. 2 pp. Photostat. Original owned by Muzeum Narodowe w Krakowie, Poland. #9013.
    Embargo and blockade prevent John Barnes from sending remittances to Kosciuszko. Insecurity of U.S. banks. Investment in Pennsylvania bank stock transferred to U.S. government loan. Peace between England and France. Great events at Paris. Mentions Mr. Morton, Boice & Kurtz, William Murdock of London, Messrs. Barings Brothers & Co. of London.
    [2868-b]
  - JOHN BARNES, Georgetown, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1814 July 7.; ALS. 4 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Remittances to Kosciuszko. Difficulties encountered and expenses incurred in conversion of Kosciuszko's bank of Pennsylvania stock into government stock. Notes that Kosciuszko's capital is increased but interest reduced by this transaction.
    [1301]
  - JOHN BARNES, Georgetown, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1814 July 13.; ALS. 4 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Growth of Philadelphia. Criticism of a gentleman not named. Great Britain's jealousy of our liberty and wealth.
    [1302]
  - PATRICK GIBSON, Richmond, to THOMAS JEFFERSON., 1814 July 13.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #5533.
    Nail rod. T. J.'s account.
    [2869]
  - JOHN BARNES, Georgetown, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1814 July 29.; ALS. 3 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Remittance to General Kosciuszko. Payment for his government stock. Result of the commissioners at Ghent awaited. Inability of Britain to subjugate the United States. References to James Monroe, Mr. Pleisentson (of Mr. Monroe's office), and William H. Crawford.
    [1303]
  - JOHN BARNES, Georgetown, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1814 July.; ALS. 3 pp. Edgehill-Randolph Papers, #1397.
    Visit from Mr. Taylor. Mr. S.'s house has fallen under the hammer of the auctioneer. Outcome of the war. Reference to Etienne Le Maire.
    [1304]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to JOHN HARTWELL COCKE, Bremo., 1814 August 5.; ALS. 1 pp. Endorsed by T. J., 38-163. Printed: B of R VI 89 (MS. in DLC). #38-163.
    Unable to pay for horse by order on Gibson & Jefferson because flour not sold. Hopes for peace.
    [1305]
  - THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello, to CRAVEN PEYTON, Monteagle., 1814 August 13.; ALS. 1 pp. #9706.
    Charles L. Lewis' deed.
    [2870-a]
  - PETER CARR, Carr's Brook, to THOMAS JEFFERSON, Monticello., 1814 August 14.; ALS. 2 pp. Endorsed by T. J. Carr-Cary Papers, #1231.
    Meeting of the committee consisting of John Winn, James Leitch, John Nicholas, [Frank] Carr, and Alexander Garrett, for viewing sites for Albemarle Academy.
    [1306]